ASHA R ROUT

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Over 7+ years of experience as Frontend developer with depth knowledge in frontend technologies like React , redux and backend technologies like Java 8.springboot . I also have working experience in Docker,kubernates , MongoDB, PostgreSQL and Mysql. My experties of work involves planning, requirements gathering, development, testing and deployment. I am seeking a challenging position with an organization where I can utilize my technical and interpersonal skills to serve the organization and enhance the same.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ASSOCIATE DEVELOPMENT

Cognizant - Feb 2021 - June 2022

- Development of React application
- Creating UI for an application based on deployment and error logging system on server using react.js .
- Creating backend using Java8 ,mongoDB and Postgressql
- Server management and deployment using Linux command and WINSCP.
- containerisation using docker
- · deployment using Kubernates and argo

FULL STACK DEVELOPER /SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Accenture - Apr 2017 - Feb 2021

- Helped design and build out a responsive framework to support the
 development of a custom global ecommerce system eventually rolled
 out to 37 countries in 26 languages. The site does an estimated 3.5Mn
 orders annually and is responsible for hundreds of millions of dollars
 in sales each year.
- Collecting requirements from stakeholders for overall site and individual features.
- Providing creative, best practices and design input to establish project goals and deliverables.
- Building rich, interactive web-based prototypes utilizing the latest Javascript, Jquery, JAVA and React js mobile technologies.
- Helping develop a responsive framework that worked on a smartphone as well as it did on tablets and desktops.
- Modularizing CSS files for maximum flexibility and usability when implementing different themes and unique configurations .
- Working with the Java developers to implement prototype elements into web applications.
- Establish the entire server for hosting Application in Remote Desktop
- I have Deployed Application on server with SSO implementation and executed vulnerability testing and resolution on them .

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

React.js.
Redux.
JDK 8
Core Java
HTML. Bootstrap
CSS. SASS.
JavaScript.
ES6
Git,
HTTP. REST
AWS
MySQL
mongoDB
PostgreSql
Docker
kubernates

PERSONAL SKILLS

Creative spirit
Reliable and professional
Organized
Time management
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated

IT DEVELOPER

Numag Data System Pvt Ltd - Mar 2015 - Mar 2017

- Provided UI/UX guidance and expertise to support their Equipment automation with a footfall of 25k .With 99% efficient software we could reduce e-bill by 2.5lac per year .
- Acted as corporate webmaster utilizing HTML, CSS and Javascript skills to build and maintain the company's customer and shareholder-facing web presence.
- Developed UI/UX solutions using industry best practices and a combination of graphic and prototype solutions to convey solution practicality and feasibility to stakeholder.
- Acted as elearning administrator developing on AWS. Utilizing that captivate for deployment through Automation

FREE LANCER

Self-Motivated - Jan 2013 - Mar 2015

- Passionate web developer, skilled in JavaScript, JQuery, and Photoshop.
- Created 10 wireframes as freelance projects for local businesses.
- Wrote a product launch website and an ecommerce web app.
- Teach regular coding sessions at local web developer meetups.
- http://www.fossips.com
 http:// myhappyessence.com/
 http://skiminds.com

EDUCATION

B.TECH. - 68%

BPUT - AE&I 2009 - 2013

INTERMEDIATE - 63%

BEMS 2006 - 2008

MATRICULATION - 73% ABUV 1996 - 2006

INTERESTS

Martial-art Gardening Dancing

STRENGTH

Team Player Imaginative Energetic Innovative Tactful & articulate

LANGUAGES

English (Professional) Hindi (Native) Oriya (Native)

CONTACT

A. Rani Rout
Aadugodi,
Bangalore
560029
M: +91-9886573848
asharout.rout@gmail.com